Once you surrender and before you die.
你们一旦未死先降
How would Trisolarans treat human prisoners of war?
三体人会怎么对待人类战俘
It's hundreds of years later..
几百年后的事
Who cares.
管他呢
Voiceprint confirmed.
声纹已确认
The excitation area is ready to begin.
激发区启动准备中
300 kA
300千安
I want a weapon
我要的是武器
and you talk to me about safety.
你和我谈安全
600 kA
600千安
Let's not talk about safety, ok?
不谈安全是吧
Then I excite the macroelectrons to the highest energy state
那我把宏电子激发到最高能量状态
800 kA
800千安
Are the experiment results still valid?
实验结果还有效吗
Polluted.
被污染了
I'm sorry.
我重新
An utter waste.
畏畏缩缩的废物
You are
就只能
only holding me back.
来拖我的后腿
Come in.
进来吧
No need to remove your shoes.
不用换鞋
Out with it.
说吧
What is it?
什么事儿
Here is a structural diagram of the space station.
空间站的结构图
You know this area better than me.
你比我熟悉
Elena is too young
埃琳娜太年轻
and has a lack of experience in space operations.
缺少太空作业的经验
I still have hope
我还是希望
you can be the leader of this project.
你能做我的实验主导人
I can't go.
不去
Of course.
当然
It can wait for you to finish your vacation.
是等你休完假
Don't bother.
不用
This experiment will fail.
这实验肯定失败
Before you do your particle collision experiment
你在做粒子对撞实验前
did you know the result?
难道就知道结果吗
So..
所以
Scientists have their assertions but,
科学家与其论断
it's better to get proof.
不如去求证
It's wasn't easy for you to travel all the way here
你大老远跑来一趟也不容易
So i'll just say it.
我就直说了吧
Trisolaran understanding of macroelectrons
三体人对宏电子的理解
is much greater than humans.
比人类高太多了
Using this weapon on them
在它们面前用这种武器
is just playing tricks.
就是班门弄斧
Ah, you don't know Luban.
你不知道鲁班
Anyway, do you think
反正就是
this experiment can succeed?
实验成不成
or have the same result.
结果都一样
I would advise you
所以我劝你
to change your mind.
换个思路吧
Dr. Ding
丁博士
you can also change your mind.
你也可以换个思路
Since the sophon lock
智子封锁后
you have nothing to study.
你们已经没有什么可以研究
The scientific research department can't even pay your salary
科研部连工资都发不出来
Not to mention experimental funding.
更别提实验经费了
You are an realistic person
你是个有理想的人
you need to take a chance.
你需要机会
I need you for my experiment.
我的实验也需要你
it's a win-win.
这是双赢
Dr. Ding
丁博士
I have said what has needed to be said.
话已经说到这个份上
I hope you will think about it.
希望你能好好考虑
Otherwise
不然
Sai can't help you either.
萨伊也帮不了你
Have you ever drank urine?
你喝过尿吗
What?
什么
Your own urine.
自己的尿
Have you ever drank it?
喝过吗
Do you know who you're talking to?
你知道自己在跟谁说话吗
What's the problem?
这有什么
I just drank it.
我就喝过啊
The kind filtered by the circulation system on the space station.
空间站循环系统过滤的那种
I drank it for more than three hundred days.
还喝了三百多天
To confirm
为了证实
those two invisible things.
那两个看不见的东西
This is who I am
这才是我
you know.
知道吗
I'm just a research nerd.
我就是个搞科研的愣头青
How much money is left..
有多大碗吃多少饭
How much can the project push.
项目能推多少是多少
Do your best and listen to destiny.
尽人事听天命呗
These days, you have to figure it out.
这年头啊得自己想得通才行
Theoretical physics
理论物理不行了
and applied physics.
还有应用物理
If applied physics doesn't work.
应用物理不行了
I can write science fiction, right?
我写科幻小说总可以了吧
The wins and losses you mention
你说的那些输赢
I do not care.
我不在乎
You know
你知道
Are you any worse than her?
你比她差在哪儿吗
A pioneering Experiment.
一个先锋的实验
Requires the experimenter to have a spirit of sacrifice.
需要实验者有牺牲精神
What I mean is..
我的意思是
even failure can destroy everything.
即使失败能摧毁一切
Nothing can shake her firm will.
也无法撼动她的坚定意志
But obviously
但很明显
you are not the same.
你不是
Rest well.
好好休息吧
Mr. Tyler
泰勒先生
The B436 project experiment has come a long way.
B436项目实验已经走得很远
No
不
It has gone too far.
是走得太远了
I advise you.
我劝你
Enough is enough.
适可而止
Professor Luo,
罗老师
It's so beautiful here.
太美了这里
Come have breakfast.
来先吃早饭
We are in a hurry.
我们赶时间
Here.
这儿啊
There are opportunities in the future.
以后有的是机会
We have a lot of plans
我们有很多安排
and many places to go.
很多地方要去
Thanks.
谢谢
Is there enough butter?
黄油够不够
There is enough.
够了
How do you like london?
你觉得伦敦好吗
I still prefer Mount Fuji.
还是喜欢富士山
I think..
我觉得
Do you get seasick?
你晕船吗
Ok, but..
还好但是
Pass her the spoon.
勺子给她递一下
Thank you.
% AI 谢谢
Brother Luo
罗老弟
almost done
差不多行了
Time to hit the road.
该上路了
Just a moment.
好好
Take your time
你不急慢慢吃
If there is a place you want to go, just tell me.
有想去的地方直接告诉我
I wanted to ask
我想问
what is my job?
我的工作是什么
It's getting late
来不及了
let's get going first.
先出发了
I'll tell you when I get there.
到地方再告诉你
Zhuang Yan.
庄颜
Hurry up.
快点儿
It's getting late.
再晚就来不及了
Where are we going?
我们去哪儿啊
To carry out the task.
去执行任务啊
Ok.
好啊
Hurry up.
快快快
Luggage, luggage.
行李行李
Where's the umbrella?
伞呢伞呢
Come back, come back.
回来回来
Watch me.
你看我
I will teach you.
我教你
Alright.
好
Help them quick.
快快快帮忙去
Professor Luo.
罗老师
Let's go.
我们走吧
For you.
给你的
Quick, quick, ice cream, ice cream.
快快快冰激凌冰激凌
The scenery here is so beautiful.
这里风景好美啊
where does this even go?
这是要去哪儿啊
When will we get to the end?
这什么时候才能到啊
Professor Luo
罗老师
For my work
我的工作
can I go to space?
得上太空吗
Do you want to?
你想去吗
Look here look here.
看这儿看这儿
No problem no problem.
没问题没问题
Professor Luo
罗老师
I'm ready
我做好准备了
huh?
什么
Ready for work.
工作的准备啊
Can you tell me now?
您现在可以告诉我了吗
This is
这个嘛
not urgent
不急
You
我
should look for inspiration.
再找找灵感
Shi Qiang
史强
I'm going to kill you.
我要杀了你
(Los Alamos: Where Discoveries Are Made!)
（洛斯阿拉莫斯：发现之地）
We have made history.
我们创造了历史
This time the model finally worked.
这次模型终于走通了
What's the matter?
怎么啦
Oh god what's going on?
天哪怎么回事啊
This here
这玩意儿
It's your nuclear explosion experiment?
就是你们的核爆实验
What are they going to do?
他们要干什么
Suspend the output module, quickly.
暂停输出模块快
Don't move.
别动
Why did he come here?
他怎么来了
Who?
谁啊
Ray Diaz.
雷迪亚兹
How did this bastard get in?
杂种怎么能进来
Of course the Wallfacers can get in.
面壁者当然能进来
The largest nuclear explosion model is 20 million tons equivalent.
最大的核爆模型是两千万吨级当量吧
I want ten times this number.
我要这个数的十倍
You have to give it to me.
你们得给我
This is a secret lab.
这是机密实验室
You are not qualified to point fingers.
你没资格指手画脚
Ok ok.
行了行了
These people are scientists
人家是科学家
Be reasonable.
要讲道理
I have a request.
我提要求
Just do it.
你们照办就行
Otherwise this laboratory
不然别说是一个实验室
or a continent
就是一个洲
or an ocean.
一个大洋
I can make them disappear from the map
我也可以让它从地图上消失
You could
有本事
But, you'd have to make me disappear first.
你先让我消失
Doctor.
博士
I haven't seen you in years.
几年不见
You are still so cold.
你还是这么可恶
What about you?
你不照样
Still so rude.
还这么粗鲁
Let's walk.
走
Accompany me to the Baisha shooting range.
陪我去白沙靶场转转
You came all this way.
你大老远来
It's not for playing in the sand, is it?
不是为了玩沙子吧
So what?
是又怎么样
I am wallfacer
我是面壁者
You can't refuse me.
你不能拒绝我
Look
你看
the way he used brush strokes.
他用晕染的方式
It embodies the halo and sense of space.
体现出光晕和空间感
Stand farther away.
站远一点
How can anyone see a picture like this?
哪有这么看画的
This kind of composition is stable and has a bit of fluidity.
这种平稳中又带点流动性的构图
Is representative of the Renaissance.
代表了文艺复兴时期
A unique aesthetic style.
特有的审美样式
Like me that morning.
就像我那天早晨
Seeing your manor the first time.
第一次看到你的庄园
viewing the lake.
和湖景一样
I like the paintings of this period the most.
所以我最喜欢这个时期的画作了
Because it's
因为那时
the first time painters
画家第一次
discovered the beauty of human beings.
发现了人类的美
What's wrong?
怎么了
Professor Luo
罗老师
You said
你说
After the Trisolarans come
三体人来了以后
can we preserve our civilization?
会保留我们的文明吗
I mean
我是说
is it possible
它们有没有可能
to keep these works of art?
保留这些艺术品
Do you know
你知道
what shows our highest respect to a civilization?
看重一个种族的最高表现
What is it?
是什么吗
The ability to kill them all.
斩尽杀绝
To a civilization,
就是对一个文明
this shows the highest respect.
最局的重视
Look at that painting.
你看那幅画
Is it..
是
Picasso?
毕加索吗
This exhibition area
这个展区
How could there be Picasso?
怎么会有毕加索啊
As soon as I saw her
一看到她
I thought of you.
我就想起了你们
me?
我们
Wallfacer.
面壁者啊
What does she have to do with the Wallfacer?
她和面壁者有什么关系啊
There is a way
有没有一种方式
people can
可以让人们
through a look
通过一个眼神
or an expression
一个表情
understand each other.
就能读懂对方
You mean
你是说
like the smile of the mona lisa
像蒙娜丽莎的微笑这样
you can only feel.
只可意会
Right.
对
This way people can escape Sophon's surveillance.
这样人们就可以摆脱智子的监视了
If eyes were so easy to read.
如果眼神那么容易就被读懂
Then why would this be such a famous painting?
那它还怎么会是名画呢
You
你
don't believe me?
不信
Look
看
You get what I mean.
你懂我的意思了
You are creating a
你是要创造一种
silent language.
无声的语言吗
Try it.
试一下嘛
Hurry up.
快点
Ok ok ok.
好好好
Then let's
那我们
try it.
试试看
Be serious.
你认真点
Say whatever you think.
怎么想就怎么说
I think you
我觉得你
are hungry
肚子饿了
or planning
正盘算
what's for dinner tonight.
今晚吃什么
Did I guess right?
猜对了是吗
How about this?
那你说
what do I want to eat.
我想吃什么
No need to guess.
这不用猜吧
You eat anything if you are hungry.
你饿了什么都吃
It's your turn to guess.
该你猜我了
You are worrying
你在发愁
how to give me a good job.
给我什么工作好
I'm not worrying about that.
我不愁这个
You are..
那就是
worried that I can't do the job well.
担心我做不好这份工作
Kind of.
还真有点儿
what is it?
到底是什么呀
Can you tell me now?
能不能先告诉我
I'll tell you when we get there.
到地方了再告诉你
Where.
哪里
The highest spot.
最高的地方
Mr. Oppenheimer
奥本海默那家伙
Right here
就是在这儿
dropped the first nuke.
投的第一颗核弹吧
in 1945.
1945年
But after Hiroshima and Nagasaki
不过广岛和长崎之后
he had regrets.
他就后悔了
No matter how terrible the weapon is
武器不管多可怕
there are positives.
总是好东西
The most powerful thing in the world now
现在世界上最厉害的
is the nuclear bomb
就是核弹
and ball lightning.
和球状闪电
Tyler is one step ahead
泰勒快了一步
you have to support me.
你得支持我
I can not do it.
我做不到
What you want is too much.
你要的当量太大了
We do not have a corresponding model.
我们没有相应的模型
You aren't telling the truth.
没说实话
After nuclear sanctions
核武制裁后
the whole world saw
全世界都看到
the look on your face.
您脸上的表情
Building nuclear weapons of this magnitude..
建造这个量级的核武器
it's a shame
只是为了一雪前耻
that my lab
我的实验室
can't live up to your ambition.
装不下您的野心
Ray Diaz
雷迪亚兹
Wallfacers and ordinary people.
面壁者和普通人的
Do you know
区别在哪儿
what the difference is?
知道吗
The problem is
找出我们的共同点
we don't even know what we have in common.
才是难题吧
There is one difference.
只有一个区别
Ordinary people see right now
普通人看眼前
but, I have to see four hundred years ahead.
但我得看四百年后
To the point.
直说吧
your lab is too small.
实验室太小
There's still not enough equipment.
还是设备不够
Despite doing research in this shitty place
虽然你在这鸟不拉屎的地方搞研究
I understand
但我很清楚
you wish the whole world knew who you were.
你巴不得全世界都知道你是谁
Similiary,
这个当量
the world will forget Oppenheimer
全世界都会忘了奥本海默
but, remember you.
而记住你
Equipment is not necessary.
设备倒不用
I just need one person.
我只需要一个人
A cosmologist.
科兹莫
Someone who studies the stars?
一个研究恒星的
Why?
为什么
The 200-megaton nuclear bomb model you want
你要的两亿吨级核弹模型
is beyond the scope of nuclear weapons.
已经超出了核武的范畴
Essentially
本质上来说
It's a model of a star.
就是一颗恒星模型
I'm very excited Rey Diaz.
我很激动雷迪亚兹
Now it is clear the significance of this project
现在看来这个项目的意义
well beyond greater the supernuke.
远远超出了建造超级核弹本身
I will become death
我正变成死亡
destroyer of worlds.
世界的毁灭者
Oppenheimer.
奥本海默
The first time a nuclear bomb exploded
第一次看到核弹爆炸
that is what was said.
就是这么说的
Ray Diaz.
雷迪亚兹
Thank you for giving me this opportunity.
谢谢你给我这个机会
what opportunity?
什么机会
The chance to make a sun.
制造太阳的机会
What we are doing
知道我们在做什么吗
is creating an artificial star.
我们在创造一颗虚拟的恒星
Ray Diaz.
雷迪亚兹
Mr. President.
总统先生
What's wrong?
您怎么了
call someone here.
快叫人过来
Yes.
是
Ray Diaz.
雷迪亚兹
Verified by a PDC spokesperson.
据PDC新闻发言人核实
Wallfacer Rey Diaz.
面壁者雷迪亚兹
Is suffering from a disease called "Sunphobia".
日前患上一种名为“恐日症”的疾病
The hidden mental illness of the Wallfacer is worrying.
面壁者的心理隐疾令人担忧
It is reported that
据悉
some Wallfacers are looking for a psychotropic drug that can prevent them from talking in their sleep.
有面壁者在寻找一种能避免自己说梦话的精神药物
Is the Wallfacer project really what it claims to be?
面壁计划是否真如当初所说
It has become the last bastion of mankind.
成为人类最后的堡垒
Still unknown.
现在还是一个未知数
The scientific Advisory Boards
据科学顾问团
chief scientist of Computer Technology disclosed
计算机技术首席科学家披露
the wallfacers plan
面壁计划中
for the stellar nuclear bomb model and the brain analysis camera requires computing power
恒星型核弹模型及大脑解析摄像机所需算力
are far beyond the the current limits of technology.
均远超目前的技术极限
Therefore
因此
At the just-held 89th Wallfacer project hearing
在刚刚召开的第八十九次面壁计划听证会上
wallfacer Rey Diaz submited a request for hibernation.
面壁者雷迪亚兹提交了冬眠申请
This comes after Hines
这是继希恩斯之后
to be the second to go the future.
第二位前往未来
Wallfacers are waiting for hope.
等待希望的面壁者
News from the Daily Verne.
来自《凡尔纳日报》消息
Crisis eras third census results have been announced.
危机纪元第三次人口普查结果揭晓
Global fertility rates hit record lows.
全球的生育率都连创新低
Falling into the lowest fertility category.
坠入低生育率陷阱
This just in. Breaking news.
现插入一则重要新闻
Wallfacer Tyler
面壁者泰勒
and its research team
及其科研团队
will go to synchronous orbit in the near future.
将于近日前往同步轨道附近
Beginning the ball lightning space experiment.
开展球状闪电太空实验
Tyler's research team claims
泰勒科研团队宣称
This experiment is not a real combat simulation.
本次实验并非实战模拟
So the strike target is going to be an unpowered spacecraft.
所以打击目标设定为无动力标靶飞船
The entire experiment will also be operated remotely
整个实验过程也将采用远程操作
to ensure the safety of researchers.
以保证实验人员的安全
In addition, the research team revealed
此外科研团队还透露
the space electromagnetic launch rail is also under construction.
太空电磁发射导轨也在建设中
The launch speed of ball lightning in space will be greatly increased.
届时球状闪电在太空中的发射速度将大幅提升
The above is the entire content of this broadcast
以上是本次播报的全部内容
For more information, please visit the official website of Verne News.
更多消息请登录凡尔纳新闻官方网站
Thank you for listening.
感谢您的收听
Goodbye.
再见
Mr. Tyler.
泰勒先生
I am..
我